The Buddha described in the Mahamangala
Suta as the first blessing, the
avoidance of fools, association with the
wise, and the honoring of that which is
worthy of honor. How do I find out what
is worthy of honor and how do I truly
venerate it?
Um well, yeah, I mean you will have to
learn about it to some extent.
Um what is what is useful? What is worth
developing? What is worth investing
effort in in terms of the the training,
in terms of the practice, in terms of
the dispassion
and then honor it by doing it,
not honor it by setting up a shrine that
you will bow to once every two weeks and
in return it will do the work for you.
So it's like have a attitude of respect
towards that which is worth developing
which is virtue
restraining of your senses
um taming down the mind and basically
aiming for dispassion in in in all areas
of your life.
So uh venerating it, respecting it in
that sense helps helps maintain the
context um helps you uh
um helps you uh
have the energy and inspiration to kind
of you know go further because you're
not you're not being casual about it.
But it does not mean as I said just sort
of um
make a shrine out of it and worship it
like a deity or some sort of holy way
and the practice and not actually be
doing it because even in the sutras they
would have said um how his disciples pay
respect to him correctly by becoming
arro. There were those statements in the
There were those statements in the
sutras when when a monk becomes an aran
and says the teacher has been respected
has been served has been uh venerated
basically like you could spend the rest
of your life bowing but if you're not
practicing makes no difference it's just
it's just an external
norm external compensation that you're
trying to to to to um engage in cause
because you're not practicing